Guide to the Kensinger Jones Papers, 1934-2001 and undated RL.00648
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Michigan State University, 1982-1997 and undated
  - Subject Files, 1982-1997 and undated
    - Kensinger and Alice Jones Endowed Visiting Advertising Professional Program, 1990-1991 (Box 43)
    - The Leavey Award for Excellence in Private Enterprise Education, Freedom Foundation, 1983-1985, Folder 1 of 2 (Box 43)
    - The Leavey Award for Excellence in Private Enterprise Education, Freedom Foundation, 1983-1985, Folder 2 of 2 (Box 44)
    - Leo Burnett Creative Development Fund, 1985 (Box 44)
    - Leo Burnett (USA) Company, correspondence re teaching materials and placement of MSU students, 1985, 1989 (Box 44)
    - Job-seeking materials for students, 1983-1991 (Box 44)
    - Journal of Advertising, Rebuilding Bridges-Guest Editorial, and What Happened to the Bridge? 1989 (Box 44)
    - Medill School of Journalism, Northwestern University, Creative Seminar, 1987 (Box 44)
    - MIPA (Michigan Interscholastic Press Association) 1988-1989, 1992-1994, 2 folders (Box 44)
    - NAMA Awards Programs, scripts, 1986-1987 (Box 44)
    - National Agri-Marketing Association, MSU Student Chapter, Jan. 23,1985 (Box 44)
    - On teaching and Advertising, in response to column Envy on Campus by B. Lauterborn, UNC-Chapel Hill [NC] undated (Box 44)
    - Poem on retirement (Box 44)
    - Professionals and Professors: A Study of Executive Career Changing in Advertising Education, report by Sandra Moriarty, 1986-1987 (Box 44)
    - Programs, Packards and Pinnacles article by Jones for The Adcrafter, undated (Box 44)
    - Rooney, William, guest lecturer, correspondence and articles, 1985-1986 (Box 44)
    - Speeches (chronological)
      - To Teach the Unteachable Star, National Advertising Agency Network, Chicago, IL, 1983 Oct. 6 (Box 44)
      - Teaching: One Way to Avoid Retirement, Kiwanis, Kalamazoo, Mich., 1984 Feb. 6 (Box 44)
      - Golden Age, Birmingham Graduate Students-MSU, 1985 Mar. 2 (Box 44)
      - Archway Cookies, 1985 Sept. 20 (Box 44)
      - Can You Teach Creativity? Marketing and Advertising Round Table (of Southwest Michigan), 18, 1986 (Box 44)
      - Managing for Creativity, Seminar for Pistachios, Pour House and Piccadilly Inn, three businesses in Lansing, Mich., 1986 Nov. 10 (Box 44)
      - Looking Both Ways at Once, Adcraft meeting, Detroit, 1987 Mar. 18 (Box 44)
      - Replicate Reality, AEJMC Convention, San Antonio, TX, 1987 Aug. 1-4 (Box 45)
      - The Case for Consanguinity, [1990] (Box 45)
      - What Recession? Dalhousie University, Halifax, Nova Scotia, 1992 Jan. 17 (Box 45)
      - Integration, Interactivity, Infomercials: The Return of the Three Magi? American Advertising Federation, District II, Atlantic City, NJ, 1994 Jan. 8 (Box 45)
      - Who Thought That Up? MSU advertising students, East Lansing, Mich., 1995 (Box 45)
      - History on Radio, (Outline of speech) Barry County Historical Society, 1995 Sept. 21 (Box 45)
      - History on Radio, Vermontville (Mich.) Historical Society, 1996 May 23 (Box 45)
      - An Adventure in Education: Twelve Days Teaching in Four Chinese Cities, [undated] (Box 45)
    - Student business cards, undated (Box 45)
    - Student correspondence, 1983-1988, 6 folders (Box 45)
    - Student correspondence, 1989-1994 and undated, 4 folders (Box 46)
    - Student correspondence
      - Caseglia, Kim, 1988-1989 (Box 46)
      - Coppola, Steve, 1984-1993 (Box 46)
      - Daykin, Bob, 1986 (Box 46)
      - Deni, Lisa, 1985-1986 (Box 46)
      - Grossman, Lisa, 1988 (Box 46)
      - Hodari, Ajili, 1990 (Box 46)
      - Lynch, Kevin, 1988-1996 (Box 46)
      - Matthew, Zach, 1988-1989 (Box 46)
      - Park, Joni, 1985 (Box 46)
      - Parker, Pam, 1986-1987 (Box 46)
      - Pung, Tanny, 1986 (Box 46)
      - Reif, Brandon, 1994-1995 (Box 46)
      - Sinsabaugh, Ginger, 1992 (Box 46)
      - Swan, Jon, 1983-1984 (Box 46)
      - Videan, Joe, 1984-1991 (Box 47)
      - Waugh, Susan (Beltari), 1986-1992 (Box 47)
      - Wicks, Jan (LeBlanc), ca. 1985 (Box 47)
      - Zywicki, Ron, 1990-1991 (Box 47)
    - Student Internship at Paul Deur Creative Group, Grand Rapids, Mich., 1988 (Box 47)
    - Successful advertising, including a memo by Leo Burnett, 1950s, 1980s (Box 47)
    - Taiwan-East Lansing Seminar, Relevant Innovation, a seven day seminar, 1989-1990, 4 folders (Box 47)
    - A Two-Track Promotion and Tenure System: Fact or Fantasy? by Don E. Schultz, Medill School of Journalism, Northwestern University, March, 1987 (Box 47)
    - U.S.-China Exchange, 1985-1989, 3 folders (Box 47)
    - VAP (Visiting Advertising Professional)-Anthony (Tony) L. Antin, 1987 May, 2 folders (Box 48)
    - VAP-Bruce Bendinger, 1988 May (Box 48)
    - VAP-Don Tennant, 1991 May (Box 48)
  - Course Materials, 1982-1995 and undated [Subseries Closed]
    Arranged chronologically by academic quarter and by course, the Course Materials Subseries pertains primarily to two advanced courses: Advertising 417-"Advanced Creative Strategy and Execution" and Advertising 441-"TV-Radio Advertising." For most courses, Jones taught over fifty students, divided into two sections. Other courses include: Advertising 317-"Creative Strategy and Execution" and after 1989-1990, Advertising 492-"Advanced Copywriting." For each course, a "Course Materials" folder typically includes a syllabus, a midterm and final exam, and for the later years, a coursepak of readings.
    Subsequent course folders pertain to student projects and are titled with the name and location of the particular advertising client or product assigned for the course. Materials typically include: 1) background information on the client or product; 2) student reports often with creative illustrations and sample advertising; 3) evaluations of the group presentations by the client, by Jones, and by the other students; and 4) peer evaluations of individual contributions to the group. During some courses, students produced video or audio tapes. On occasion, selected student projects were presented at state or regional competitions. (A folder at the beginning of this subseries contains chronological and alphabetical listings of the student project assignments.)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Restrictions on Access: Subseries is closed pending review by collector.
    - Student Creative Projects, 1982-1987 (Box 48)
    - 1982 Spring
      - Adv 441 - TV-Radio Advertising: Course materials (Box 48)
      - Adv 441 - Lecture notes (Box 48)
      - Adv 441 - Guest Speakers (Box 48)
      - Adv 441 - Student Essays on Four Guest Speakers (Box 48)
      - Adv 441 - Say Yes to Michigan - Michigan Dept. of Commerce (Box 48)
    - 1982 Fall (Box 49)
      - Adv 417 - Advanced Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials (Box 49)
      - Adv 441 - TV Radio Advertising: Course materials (Box 49)
      - Adv 417 and 441 - Oldsmobile, Firenza - Leo Burnett-GM Intercollegiate Marketing Competition, 3 folders (Box 49)
    - 1983 Winter
      - Adv 417 - Advanced Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials (Box 49)
      - Adv 417 - Diet Squirt (Box 49)
      - Adv 441 - TV-Radio Advertising: Course materials (Box 49)
      - Adv 441 - Archway Cookies (Box 49)
    - 1983 Spring
      - Adv 417 - Advanced Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials (Box 49)
      - Adv 417 - Kellogg Nutrigrain (Box 49)
      - Adv 441 - TV-Radio Advertising: Course materials (Box 49)
      - Adv 441 - Wharton Center (MSU) (Box 49)
    - 1983 Fall
      - Adv 417 - Advanced Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials (Box 49)
      - Adv 417 - Channel 41 (WUHQ-TV) (Box 50)
      - Adv 441 - TV-Radio Advertising: Course materials (Box 50)
      - Adv 441 - American Tourister - Campbell-Ewald Collegiate Cable Competition (Box 50)
    - 1984 Winter
      - Adv 417 - Advanced Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials (Box 50)
      - Adv 417 - MSU Student Housing Corporation, 3 folders (Box 50)
      - Adv 441 - TV-Radio Advertising: Course materials (Box 50)
      - Adv 441 - Asgrow Seeds (Upjohn) Kalamazoo (Box 50)
    - 1984 Spring
      - Adv 417 - Advanced Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials (Box 50)
      - Adv 417 - Holland Hitch (Box 50)
      - Adv 441 - TV-Radio Advertising: Course materials (Box 50)
      - Adv 441 - MSU Public Relations Student Recruiting, 3 folders (Box 51)
    - 1984 Fall
      - Adv 441 - TV-Radio Advertising: Course materials (Box 51)
      - Adv 441 - Felspausch Food Store (opening) Mason, Mich. (Box 51)
    - 1985 Winter
      - Adv 441 - TV-Radio Advertising: Course materials (Box 51)
      - Adv 441 - Bike to Work Day - Michigan Dept. of Transportation (Box 51)
    - 1985 Spring
      - Adv 417 - Advanced Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials (Box 51)
      - Adv 441 - TV-Radio Advertising: Course materials (Box 51)
      - Adv 441 - Muskegon County Museum, 4 folders (Box 52)
    - 1985 Fall
      - Adv 317 - Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials (Box 52)
      - Adv 441 - TV-Radio Advertising: Course materials (Box 52)
      - Adv 441 - Proline Archery (bow hunting) (Box 52)
    - 1986 Winter
      - Adv 417 - Advanced Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials (Box 52)
      - Adv 417 - State Room - Kellogg Center - MSU, 2 folders (Box 52)
      - Adv 441 - TV-Radio Advertising: Course materials (Box 52)
      - Adv 441 - National Car Rental - Campbell-Ewald Cable Competition, 2 folders (Box 52)
    - 1986 Spring (Box 53)
      - Adv 417 - Advanced Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials (Box 53)
      - Adv 417 - Extra Credit Assignment (Box 53)
      - Adv 417 - MSU-Instructional Television and extra credit assignment, 3 folders (Box 53)
      - Adv 441 - TV-Radio Advertising: Course materials (Box 53)
      - Adv 441 - Borgess Mental Health Center, Inc., 3 folders (Box 53)
    - 1986 Fall
      - Adv 417 - Advanced Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials (Box 53)
      - Adv 417 - Riverwalk Theatre, 3 folders (Box 53)
      - Adv 441 - TV-Radio Advertising: Course materials (Box 53)
      - Adv 441 - Chevrolet Trucks, '88 model, 2 folders (Box 54)
    - 1987 Winter
      - Adv 417 - Advanced Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials (Box 54)
      - Adv 417 - Casa de Pasta, Lansing, Mich., 3 folders (Box 54)
    - 1987 Winter
      - Adv 441 - TV-Radio Advertising: Course materials (Box 54)
      - Adv 441 - Archway Cookies (Box 54)
    - 1987 Spring
      - Adv 417 - Advanced Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials (Box 54)
      - Adv 417 - Abrams Planetarium, Folder 1 of 2 (Box 54)
      - Adv 417 - Abrams Planetarium, Folder 2 of 2 (Box 55)
    - 1987 Fall
      - Adv 417 - Advanced Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials, 2 folders (Box 55)
      - Adv 417 -- Michigan Beef Industry Commission, 2 folders (Box 55)
      - Adv 441 - TV-Radio Advertising: Course materials (Box 55)
      - Adv 441 - WILS Radio Station, Lansing Mich. (Box 55)
    - 1988 Winter
      - Adv 417 - Advanced Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials (Box 55)
      - Adv 417 - Technical Assistance Center (computers) East Lansing, Mich. (Box 56)
      - Adv 441 - TV-Radio Advertising: Course materials (Box 56)
      - Adv 441 - MSU Snack Shops - Residence Halls, 3 folders (Box 56)
    - 1988 Spring
      - Adv 417 - Advanced Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials, 2 folders (Box 56)
      - Adv 417 - Cheap Shots gun shop, Haslett, Mich., 2 folders (Box 56)
    - 1988 Summer (Box 57)
      - Adv 317 - Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials (Box 57)
      - Adv 317 - Handouts about how to make an ad (Box 57)
    - 1988 Fall
      - Adv 317 -- Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials (Box 57)
      - Adv 317 - Public Service announcements (PSA Assignment), 13 folders (Box 57)
    - 1989 Winter
      - Adv 317 -- Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials (Box 57)
      - Adv 317 - Student report about Ken Jones as a lifelong writer (Box 57)
    - 1989 Spring
      - Adv 317 -- Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials (Box 57)
      - Adv 317 - Public Service Announcements (Box 57)
    - 1989 Fall (Box 58)
      - Adv 417 - Advanced Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials (Box 58)
    - 1990 Fall
      - Adv 417 - Advanced Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials (Box 58)
    - 1991 Spring
      - Adv 417 - Advanced Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials (Box 58)
      - Adv 417 - Silver Dollar, bar and night spot, East Lansing, Mich. (Box 58)
    - 1991 Fall
      - Adv 417 - Advanced Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials (Box 58)
    - 1992 Spring
      - Adv 417 - Advanced Creative Strategy and Execution: Course materials (Box 58)
      - Adv 417 - Advanced Creative Strategy and Execution: Correspondence, notes, and articles (Box 58)
    - 1992 Fall
      - Adv 492 - Advanced Copywriting: Course materials (Box 58)
      - Adv 492 - Chair - student assignment (Box 58)
      - Adv 492 - "Name that Barn" birthday card with windows and flaps (Box 58)
    - 1993 Spring
      - Adv 492 - Advanced Copywriting: Course materials (Box 58)
    - 1993 Fall
      - Adv 492 - Advanced Copywriting: Course materials (Box 58)
    - 1994 Fall
      - Adv 492 - Advanced Copywriting: Course materials (Box 58)
    - 1995 Fall
      - CAS 492 - Advanced Copywriting: Course materials (Box 58)
      - CAS 492 - McDonalds College Program, 2 folders (Box 58)
      - CAS 492 - Promotional Products and Hyatt Hotels (Box 58)
    - Undated course materials [undated] (Box 58)
    - Evaluations, 1983-1995, 4 folders (Box 59)
      Student evaluations and grades are restricted.
    - Grades 1982-1988, 4 folders (Box 60)
- Writings and Speeches, 1944-2001 and undated, bulk 1955-1972
  Divided into four subseries: Speeches, Published Articles, Other Writings, St. Louis; and Other Writings, 1960-2001 and undated This series documents Jones's continuous dedication to writing. The bulk of the materials, 1955-1972, correspond to his advertising interests and consist of text and correspondence related to speeches (written for himself and occasionally for others) and related to articles submitted for publication. See also the Audiovisual Series for slides, films, videos, and audio products, which may relate to speeches.
  - Speeches, 1955-1974 and undated
    Arranged chronologically, the Speeches Subseries contains the text and correspondence for speeches (written for himself and occasionally for others) to be delivered at advertising conferences, creative seminars, schools, or civic events. A chronological list compiled by Jones is in a folder at the beginning of the series; the same folder also contains a copy of this list annotated during processing regarding the presence or absence of folders and speeches.
    - Personal Catalog Listing of Speeches (1955 - 1972), Published Articles (1959-1972), and Communications Conferences (1962-1966) (Box 61)
    - 1955
      - Television Commercials From Confusion to Conclusion: Advertising Executives Club of Chicago, Mar. 8 (Box 61)
    - 1957
      - Development of a Television Commercial: Commonwealth Edison - Little Bill Spots. Schury High School, Jun. 13 (Box 61)
      - Creation of Television's and Radio's Advertising Effectiveness, Kroger General Office Meeting, [Detroit] Nov.5 (Box 61)
    - 1959
      - The Madison Avenue Myth: speech for T. B. Adams, Campbell-Ewald Co. [May 26, written by Jones et al.] (Box 61)
      - The Mightiest Law of All: speech for Roger Kyes, General Motors. Jul. 7 (Box 61)
      - How to Create More Effective Radio Commercials. Advertising Age Creative Seminar Workshop, Chicago, Aug.7 (Box 61)
      - Midsummer Night's Dilemma: speech for T. B. Adams Campbell-Ewald Company [National Association of Broadcasters, Fall conference Chicago], Oct. 20 (Box 61)
      - New Dollars: speech by [E.A. (Bud)] Schirmer, Campbell-Ewald. Nov. (Box 61)
    - 1960
      - Who Needs Pictures? Chicago Copywriters Club. (plus correspondence and news clips), Jan. 5 (Box 61)
      - Who Needs Pictures? Toledo Advertising Club (see 1960 Jan. 5 for speech version.), Jan. 20. Includes rewrite for Sponsor magazine. (Box 61)
      - Correspondence, new articles, and AAAA bulletin related to the role of advertisers to create an Image of Freedom and America. [Folder Title: "T.B. Adams Speech ('The Vulgarians') Image of Freedom," Aug. (Box 61)
      - Bouquets and Brickbats: speech by Gail Smith, Director of Television Advertising, General Motors Corporation [for AAAA [American Association of Advertising Agencies], Eastern Conference] Note by G. Smith indicates Jones contribution, Nov. 3 (Box 61)
    - 1961
      - Truth or Consequences? (Form and Function in Advertising): AAAA - Rocky Mountain Council, Denver; plus correspondence and news, Feb. 13 (Box 61)
      - How to Stop Playing Musical Chairs with Manpower: speech by John W. Crawford, Head Department of Advertising, Michigan State University. AAAA - Cleveland Council, Cleveland Sheraton Hotel, Feb.20 (Box 61)
      - Commercial Advertising and the Fine Arts. Eastern Michigan League, Student Council Conference, Hazel Park High School, Apr. 13 (Box 61)
      - Don't Expect Too Much of Advertising: speech by James B. Somerall, [owner/manager Pepsi Cola Franchise], Detroit Sales Promotion Executive Club; includes memo, May 25 (Box 61)
      - How to Become a Millionaire - or Should You? Masons, Perfection Lodge, No 496, F. and A.M., Detroit, Sept. 27 (Box 61)
      - From Idea to Production: speech by E.A. Schroeder, V.P., Director of Art, Campbell-Ewald Co. Women's Advertising Ad Forum, Detroit, Nov.27 (Box 61)
      - A Ph.D. Gets the ABC's of Advertising radio script for WQRS, Detroit; Revision of How to be a Millionaire - Or Should You? speech for high schools about advertising written by Donald P. David [and Jones?], Dec. (Box 61)
      - The Care and Feeding of Creativity (Box 61)
    - 1962
      - Truth or Consequences: Form and Function in Advertising AAAA [American Association of Advertising Agencies], Southeast Council, Atlanta, Feb. 16 (Box 61)
      - Truth and Consequences correspondence re revision for publication by AAAA, May (Box 61)
      - Selling By Design: Industrial Designers' Institute of Detroit, Jun. 5 (Box 61)
      - Truth and Consequences: Form and Function in Advertising: Campbell-Ewald Company, Jun. 11 (Box 61)
      - The Cost of Conflict (used with the film Creativity) Advertising Age Fifth Annual Workshop on Creativity, Chicago, Aug. 1 (Box 62)
      - Speech for T.B. Adams, Florida Fruit and Vegetable Association, 1962 Sept. 20 Annual Convention, Miami Beach, Fla.; "Rough Draft 9/10/62," Sept. 10 (Box 62)
    - 1963
      - The View from the Driver's Seat: speech by A.G. (Tony) DeLorenzo, V.P. General Motors. Wisconsin Safety Conference, Milwaukee, Wisc.; includes memos (Box 62)
      - Advertising - Saint or Sinner?: speech by John W. Crawford, Chairman, Dept. of Advertising, Division of Mass Communications, Michigan State University. Provost's Lecture Series, "Responsibility in Mass Communications," Apr.24 (Box 62)
      - Whatever Happened to Mrs. Momiyama? Detroit Country Day School, May 10. (Originally illustrated with slides; eventually reformatted as an educational filmstrip for public schools, produced by AAAA. (Box 62)
      - Remarks by John F. Gordon. General Motors [no title] Public Relations Divisional Conferences, May 27 (Box 62)
      - Why I'd Like to Talk to High School Students: speech at Northwood Institute Jul. 7 [titled folder, empty] (Box 62)
      - American TV Commercials Festival (Introduction remarks to reel of film with 1963 TV commercials) Adcraft Club Detroit, Oct. 11 (Box 62)
      - The High Cost of Conflict (shown w/ creativity film) Peoria Advertising and Selling Club, Oct. 21 (Box 62)
      - The High Cost of Conflict. (Shown w/ creativity film) Eastern Michigan University, Dec. 11 (Box 62)
      - [Text of speech and notation of visuals] for Gal Smith, [General Motors Advertising Evaluations] (Box 62)
    - 1964
      - Those Hidden Persuaders: The Ladies (two versions: one with creativity film, one w/out) includes memos 1963 Dec. re examples of advertising for women. The Mail Advertising Club of Chicago, Jan. 8 (Box 62)
      - Blow Your Horn: speech by Malcolm M. Barnum, VP Campbell-Ewald, Lakeland Rotary Club, Lakeland, Fla., Jan. 14 (Box 62)
      - How to Create Better Visuals (shown w/ slides) National Newspaper Promotion Association, Minneapolis, May 19 (Box 62)
      - [no title] "Re writing and communications; [Jones article on the] World's Fair [with color slides]" Publications Workshop, Northwood Institute, Midland, Mich., Jun. 26 (Box 62)
      - What I Wish I Could Tell Night School Students Advertising Seminar [2nd annual] for High School Administrators. Advertising School. Northwood Institute, Midland, Mich., Jul. 13 (Box 62)
      - Why I'd Like to Talk to High School Students (Seminar for High School Vocational Counselors) Oakland University, Oakland, Mich., Oct. 19 (Box 62)
      - Speech by E. A. Trombley, Campbell-Ewald Co., [no title; about the use of 3 and 4 color ROP (Run Of Press) International Newspaper Color Association Meeting, Miami, Fla., Oct. 22 and Oct. 23 (Box 62)
      - The Importance of Being Interesting: Advertising Writers Club of St. Louis, Oct. 23 (Box 62)
      - The Importance of Being Interesting: Detroit Edison Company [hosting a meeting of the] Michigan Restaurant Association, Detroit, Oct. 27 (Box 62)
      - There's No Color Like Newspaper Color: National Newspaper Advertising Seminar New York, Oct. 29 (Box 62)
    - 1965 (Box 63)
      - The Importance of Being Interesting: AAAA - 1965 Annual Meeting Greenbrier. White Sulphur Springs, West Va. Correspondence, Apr.23, 2 folders (Box 63)
      - The Importance of Being Interesting: (same version as 1965 Apr. 23 at AAAA) Fifth Annual Hatch Awards [for Creative Excellence in Advertising] dinner. Advertising Club of Greater Boston, May 24 (Box 63)
      - [Follow the Rugged Road] Annual Re-Charting Meeting, Boy Scouts of America, Northridge District, Dondero High School, Royal Oak, Mich., Aug.24 (Box 63)
      - "The Minstrel Principle": AAAA East Central Region, Annual Meeting Pittsburgh, Nov. 17 (Box 63)
    - 1966
      - "The Minstrel Principle": (original speech 1965 Nov. 17 with new introduction and conclusion) Sales Promotion Executive Association, Detroit. Workshop Sheraton Cadillac, Detroit, Jan.20 (Box 63)
      - Mules Aren't Really Deaf: outline of Speech for Colonel Willard Rockwell, Rockwell Company. Automotive Old Timers Meeting, 28th annual Luncheon, Jan. 29 (Box 63)
      - Whatever Happened to Mrs. Momiyama: Adcraft Club of Detroit; Statler Hilton Hotel, Detroit, May 13 (Box 63)
      - The Creative Process in the Ad Agency: ANPA [RI]/AAAA Seminar, re the use of Adpro links in RoPcolor newspaper ads. (American Newspaper Publishers Association - Research Institute) Hotel Ponchatrain, Detroit, Oct. 13 (Box 63)
      - The Minstrel Principle. (With slides and 7 ½" audio tape) Detroit Copy Club. Scarab Club, Detroit, Nov. 22 (Box 63)
    - 1967
      - Some Words on Wheels by the Man from Motown. [Text of speech lacking, including press release; correspondence, Public Utilities Advertising Association and Program] forty-fifth Annual Convention, St. Louis, May 12 (Box 63)
      - The Minstrel Principle: Toledo Advertising Club, Nov. 15 (Box 63)
      - Miscellaneous Speeches: printed copies of speeches [by others on subjects of interest to Jones] with memos and correspondence, 1962-1967 (Box 63)
    - 1968
      - Introductory Remarks for Speaker Ross Barrett, President of Foster and Kleiser, Los Angeles. (Barrett associated with Outdoor Advertising) Detroit Rotary Club, Jan. 24. (Box 63)